I've been worrying
当时你跟我说
about it, the moment
其实我心里头
you told me the news.
打了个鼓
By then, I thought that
我就想
it's not the right time to speak out.
现在说合不合适
An just got pregnant
安安刚怀孕
and you don't even know it's gender...
你男孩女孩也不知道
I don't care about it.
你管他男孩女孩呢
Neither do I.
不是我管男孩女孩
I'm just saying, now, it still
就是这个孩子
is an embryo
还没来到这个世界上
and you want to,
我们就给人家
you know, An's telling him...
安安就谈这事
it's not...we should do this.
真是 我们不应该
What would
你说
Li Lin think?
人家李临会咋想啊
He's a good man.
人李临知书达理的
I believe
我觉得他
he would agree.
他肯定会同意
You know nothing about men.
你根本不懂男人的心思
Listen to me,
我跟你说
men and women are
男人跟女人的
thinking differently.
想法不一样
You don't really know
你不知道李临
what he's thinking, right?
是怎么想的吧
Of course, I don't.
那我当然不知道
Okay.
好
Well,
这样
you'll pretend An,
一会儿 你演安安
and I'll be Li Lin.
我演李临
Then,
然后
you reveal the proposal of yours.
你就跟我说这件事情
What...
不是
- What are you... - Well.
不是 你
Listen
你听我说
to me firstly.
你听我说完 听我说完
I just want to show you
我只想让你知道
what would Li Lin do.
李临 会是什么态度
Then, you wouldn't blame An for it.
你就不会再埋怨安安了
Remember, we are staging a drama,
咱们现在演的是电视剧
not the musical we did
不是咱俩在
when we were young,
宣传队的时候跳的舞
with singing and dancing.
你演喜儿 我演大春
That's musical.
那是舞蹈
Understood?
明白了吧
Alright.
行行行
I'll do it.
演演演 演
But only once.
演一遍啊
OK.
来
And keep it down.
小点声啊
Or, others would think
你叫人看见
we're mental.
人以为咱俩精神病呢
OK.
好
Alright. Let's do it here.
好 就在江边上
I'm Li Lin.
我是李临
Go.
来 来
You'll approach from there.
你从那儿过来
You're An, remember.
你演安安 别忘
I didn't
我还没
say action!
喊开始呢
I need to pose like I'm thinking.
沉思一会儿啊
Li Lin.
李临
An.
安安
There's something I want to tell you.
跟你说个事
You left work early. What's wrong?
你这么早下班了呀
Well, we're about to
那个 咱不是老二
have our second child, right?
快出生了吗
I was thinking that
到时候
maybe,
能不能
he or she would take my last name.
姓许
You agree, right?
行是吧
Told you...
你看 我就说
An,
安安
are you out of your mind?
你这是 发烧啊
Stop talking nonsense.
你这不是说胡话呢吗
Why would our child take your family name?
谁跟谁姓许啊
Remember my name?
我姓啥你都忘了
L-I, Li.
我姓木子李
I'm Li Lin.
我叫李临
Man of the house.
是你丈夫
Yeah, I know.
对呀 没错呀
Then, what do you mean?
那你啥意思啊
Whose idea is this?
谁的主意
Yours?
你的主意
Your father's?
你爸的主意
Your mother's?
还是你妈的主意
Or, your whole family agree with it?
还是你们全家的主意
Stop it!
别说我们全家
So, you think
你觉得这个孩子
I couldn't provide a good life
来到这个世界上了
for the child, right?
我就养活不起吗
You think I can't support family?
我没有这个能力吗
It's not what you think.
跟养没关系
What is it, then?
那你什么意思
Then, why,
为什么要
why does my kid to take your family name?
为什么要姓许呢
But our neighbor, Wang,
你看那个隔壁老王家
the second child of her daughter
他女儿那个生那老二
took his name.
他就跟着他们家姓
Wang?
隔壁老王
What's this got to do with him?
是你家二大爷吗
Why should we do as his daughter do?
你张口隔壁老王
The Wangs' life has nothing to do with us!
闭口隔壁老王
You believe I can't afford my family?
你觉得养活不起了吗
What are you talking about?
你这想哪儿去了
Do you think that
我是你们家
I'm living off your family?!
倒插门的女婿吗
Keep it down.
小点声
Am I living
我是你家
off your family?
倒插门的女婿吗
It's not what I mean.
没这么说呀
Am I a loser who depends on my wife?
你们家娶的我吗
No...How could you even think like that?
你怎么想的
It must be your father's idea.
肯定是你爸
He's over 60
你爸六十多了
and doesn't have a son.
没儿子
Is he?
是不是
He goes on and on about
成天叨咕着
how pathetic he is, because he doesn't have a son
我没儿子 我好可怜哪
and nobody would take care of him.
我怎么养老啊
Once he knows we have the second child,
知道怀老二了
he wants the kid to take his name.
想让跟你们家姓
Don't even think about it!
想都不要想
No way!
没门
It's irrational!
你这是无理取闹
It's ridiculous!
无事生非
It's preposterous!
无中生有
Enough!
行了
See?
明白了吧
That's what Li Lin would do.
这就是李临的态度
This
我
will
你
build a wall between
老丈人和丈母娘
us and our in-laws.
是不跟姑爷有隔阂了
They would think
人家觉得
that we're
我们这两个老人
causing troubles.
不懂事
We're selfish
太自私
and think only about what we want,
什么事都为自己想
not what our children want.
不考虑小的的心
Alright. That's it.
行了 行了 行了
You are the thoughtful one, okay?
就你会做老好人
That's not what I mean.
不是 不是
I'm worrying about our daughter.
将来姑娘在中间怎么做
Between her parents and husband,
妻子不是妻子
between her two families,
姑娘不是姑娘
what could she do?
弟妹不是弟妹的
It would be a mess.
很麻烦
So, all in all,
总而言之 言而总之
in the end,
归根到底
that's my fault.
这事就是我欠考虑
You did this for me.
都怪我 你是为我好
Of course, I did this for you.
我肯定是为你好
Yeah. Though I'm the man of the house,
对 我是一家之主
anything happen isn't up to me,
但是我不做主
it's up to you.
是你做主
Look, this one is on me.
但这事我也有责任
So, don't feel bad.
你就别难过
I'm not. Why should I?
我不难过 我不难过
This is...
这事
I'm telling you,
反正我跟你说
there's plenty of time.
时间还长着呢
I still have chance
我还有机会
to convince them.
慢慢跟他们商量
Maybe they'll agree.
这事没准能成
Such a time wasting.
白演了
What did you say?
不是 老许
Time wasting?
什么叫白演了
I did this for you!
还不是为你们家
For your family!
老许家好啊
For the Xus!
老许家
[Haowen, hold him for me, please.]
浩文 抱下孩子
[Slow down.]
慢点啊
[Careful.]
看着点
[Happy now?]
开不开心哪
[Yeah.]
开心
[Let's get some treats for you.]
妈妈带你买好吃的
An,
弟妹啊
what do you want to do with the turtle?
那甲鱼你想怎么吃
How about we ask him when he comes back?
要不等李临回来再说
Then, I'll make some flapjacks for you.
那我先给你烙点饼
Li Lin can do anything but flapjacks!
李临就是不会烙饼啊
Well, I can!
姐拿手啊
Just give me a few minutes.
等着啊
Okay.
好
Turtle and flapjacks,
甲鱼就烙饼
marvelous.
绝了
What's this?
什么玩意儿这是
[Slow down.]
慢点啊
[Careful.]
小心点
[Happy now?]
开不开心哪
[Yeah.]
开心
[Let's get some treats for you.]
妈妈带你买好吃的
What are you doing here?
你坐这儿干吗呢
What do you want this time?
你又想闹什么呀
An,
姐
this time is real.
这次是真的
Just, stop being
你这一天天的
so suspicious.
能不能不要胡思乱想啊
I'm not!
我没有
I know this woman.
这女的我认识
She's Jia's ex.
是老贾的前女友
They'd been together for years.
两个人在一起很多年
Where are they now?
那他们人呢
Is it possible that
你说这孩子
these kids are Jia Haowen's?
会不会是贾浩文的
I don't think so.
应该不会吧
If you're so concerned about it,
要是那什么的话
let's take a closer look.
就进去看看呗
If you have any question,
有什么话
just ask them face-to-face.
问清楚不就完了吗
If the kids are his,
万一是真的
what should I do?
怎么办
Leave him.
那就不过了呗
Take everything he has.
让他净身出户
There is no other way.
这还有什么好商量的吗
How about
你这样
you wait here,
你在这儿等着
and I'll go in there.
我去
He's my husband.
他是我老公
I need to go.
我得去
Well,
不是
Xin,
心心啊
just think about it.
你可得想好啊
If
万一
you see things you shouldn't see,
看到什么不该看的画面
what would you do?
你怎么办
Tear him apart.
撕了他
Xin,
心
An,
姐
what are you doing here?
你们怎么来了
What are you doing here?
你这干吗呢
Nothing.
我没干什么啊
In a meeting with...
这不谈事
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
For all years, you've been lying to me!
你骗了我这么多年
You told me, you haven't had
你不是说你跟她
contact with her for years!
没有联系吗
Xin,
心
what are you talking about?!
你说啥呢
What are you doing?
你干吗呢
Why are you filming?
拍什么呢
Don't touch my sister!
你干吗扒拉我姐
Who are you?
你谁呀
I'm his wife! Who are you?
我是他老婆 你谁呀
That's it. Xin.
行了 心
What are you doing here!?
你干吗呢你
[What are you talking about?!]
谁呀
[Xin, you're mistaken.]
心 你误会了心
Get out!
出去
What?
叫谁出去呢
You are here alone with my husband!
你跟我老公在一个房间
Take your sister, get out of here!
你跟着你姐给我滚出去
Who do you think you are!
你叫谁滚出去
Xin, you're misreading the situation.
心 误会了
[Jia Haowen!]
贾浩文
Do you beg
你请我过来
my whole family here, just to
就是来恶心我们全家的
humiliate us?
是吧
No, it's not like that.
没有 没有 没有
Nobody begs you here!
谁请你过来
Bah!
不要脸
Whose kids are they?
这谁的孩子呀这
Xin...
心
Their father is not your concern.
你管得着吗 这谁孩子
Xin, you misunderstand.
误会了 心
[I'm not leaving!]
我不出去
What's wrong?
怎么了
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
You begged me here,
你求我
so I came, with my husband,
我带着我老公
for the cooperation you mentioned.
跟你来谈合作
How dare you to humiliate us like this?
你在这儿恶心谁呢
It's not...Xin...
不是 心
Get out! Now!
出去 滚出去
Sorry, bro.
妹夫 对不起 妹夫
My wife, she has depression.
我媳妇有点抑郁症
It's caused by her pregnancy...
她那个怀孕
I don't have depression!
谁抑郁症
That's how you
你就是这么
treat your guests, right?
尽地主之谊的是吧
Great! Really great.
好好好
Leave, Jia Haowen.
贾浩文 出去
We should go now.
咱们走 走走
What are you hollering for?
你跟谁吼呢
You are making troubles out of nothing!
你在这儿无理取闹
Trouble my a*s.
怎么了
Stop yelling!
别在这儿无理取闹
Chill. Chill.
冷静 冷静
Carry her out! Now!
把她扛出去 扛出去
I'm so sorry. We made a mistake.
不好意思啊 误会
Save it!
你跟谁呀
We don't need your apology!
轮得着你吗
[Out!]
滚出去
No! You get out!
谁滚出去
[What's wrong with you!]
干吗呀这是
[Jia Haowen!]
贾浩文
[You lose!]
你行啊
[Remember what]
你之前怎么
[did you tell me?]
跟我说来着的
You promised that
信誓旦旦地跟我说
you haven't contacted her for ten years!
跟前女友十年不联系了
You called that 'haven't contacted'?
你这叫不联系啊
You are seeing each other!
面都见上了
Furthermore,
你不但见了面
you held her kids as they were your own!
你还给人抱孩子
What were you thinking?
你怎么想的
How did you know it?
你怎么知道啊
She hired someone to watch you.
她找人偷拍你了
When was that?
什么时候的事啊
None of your business!
你管什么时候呢
What? You don't want to be watched by me?
我不能拍你啊
I want to. Please watch me.
拍拍拍 拍拍拍
Since I can look through your phone
你手机我都看呢
I also can watch you whenever I want!
我拍不了吗
Go ahead. Do whatever you want.
拍拍拍
Of course you should watch me, honey.
你拍是应该的啊 媳妇
Just tell me,
你跟我说实话
do you regret to marry me
人俩孩子都有了
so you invited her here,
你还跟人约着见面
even though she's already married?
你是不是心里意难平
Please,
你赶快跟她
tell her it's not what you mean
好好解释一下
and she will let it go.
这事就了了
An,
姐
I swear to god,
我什么怎么就
I've never regret!
怎么就意难平
This is...
你可真
Those two are kind of
人家两口子做贸易
big shot in the trading industry.
做得特别大
I begged them to here and work with me.
姐 我是把人求着来
There are many big shots
做贸易做得大的人
in that industry,
多得去呢
why didn't you ask others to come?
你挨个儿求啊
I believe there are always other choices.
除了他俩没别人啦
Why did you choose your ex?
非要找前女友啊
Don't you have other choices?
世界上做生意的死绝啦
Are other people all dead?
找不着人啦
Stop there.
行了 行了
Really, that's enough.
差不多得了啊
So,
那个
can we do something to fix it?
还能挽回吗
Fix it?
姐 我的姐
How?
这咋挽回
It's done. I'm done.
这不都 黄了都
Just, forget about it.
算了吧就
If you say so.
算了就算了吧
Actually, Xin's concern is
心心说得也不是
reasonable.
一点道理都没有
Yes, I know.
是 是 姐
I did make
这事啊
an ill-considered decision.
我做得确实欠考虑
In fact, I'm happy that
不过她这样
she yelled at me for that.
我还挺高兴的
Happy? What for?
有什么好高兴的呀
She did that
这不心里
because she loves me too much.
在乎我吗
You two are just
你俩要不是两口子
perfect to each other.
真是天理难容
Alright.
行了
I'll take care of her.
你别理她了
You can go now.
走吧
So, I'll leave her in your hands.
这事 交给你了
Just go.
甭管了
Leave her to me.
交给我
Thank you so much, An.
辛苦你了 姐
Go.
快走
Where are you going, Jia Haowen?
上哪儿去啊 贾浩文
Ask yourself.
你说上哪儿去
I'm not finished here!
我说完了吗
[Enough.]
你干吗呢
Stop it!
没完没了了 是吧
I'm not finished!
我还没跟他说完呢
Where is he going?
他上哪儿去啊
What's to finish?
还说什么呀
You said enough.
有什么好说的
You found him
看都看了 见也见了
and the truth,
事也弄清楚了
what else do you want?
你还想怎么的
Let's go home.
跟我回家
I want to go to mom and dad's.
我要回爸妈家
What? After torturing your poor husband,
祸祸完贾浩文
your poor parents become your next target?
祸祸老头老太太
What do you want?
你到底想干吗
Is this not enough?
闹够了没有
Get in the car.
上车
We can go.
走了
Alright.
行了
Calm down.
别生气了
I'm sorry, OK?
姐跟你道歉还不行吗
I know
你这歉道得
you don't mean to apologize.
一点都不诚恳
C'mon, I do!
你还让我怎么诚恳啊
You are glowing
老贾没事
once you know Jia doesn't have an affair.
你心里都乐开花了
And you still want to hear my apology.
还说我不诚恳
Tell me,
我问你个事
whose last name
你们家这二胎生出来
would your second child choose?
想姓什么呀
What do you mean?
你这话什么意思啊
What to choose?
什么叫想姓什么呀
Jia, of course.
那当然得姓贾了
What's wrong with you?
你这话问得有毛病吧你
Are you saying
你是觉得
just because I suspect my man has an affair,
刚陪我抓完奸之后
I have an affair myself?
我在外头也有人是吧
No. That's not what I mean.
不不不 那肯定不是的
I'm just wondering,
就是想说
have you ever thought
你就没想让他姓点
to let the kid take another last name.
别的什么的
What else could the kid take?
那还能姓什么呀
Like,
姓个
Xu?
许什么的
Why?
为啥要姓许啊
I'm an emotional challenge and I know it.
我这人平时是作了一点
But, I know
但是在大事上
right and wrong.
我从来不会无理取闹的
The child's surname
那老贾的孩子
must be the same as the dad's.
必须姓贾啊
So, mum didn't ask you?
那妈都没跟你提过吗
For what?
她为啥要跟我提啊
Did she tell you that?
她跟你提啦
No.
没有
Or,
她要跟我提
she's asking too much from me.
那就是欺负人了
Pushing me around 'cause I'm her daughter.
柿子挑软的捏
Then, why did you ask me about it?
那你在这儿没话找话呢
Trying to ease the tension.
想缓和气氛呀
In your dreams.
做梦
Sir, go faster.
那个司机你快点开
OK.
好
It's the progesterone.
一定是孕激素的问题
It's the progesterone talking.
孕激素
It's all progesterone's fault.
孕激素太高了
And she's talking out loud.
她还说出声来
Does she think I'm deaf?
太欺负人了
Auntie, I'm home.
表姑 我回来啦
Smells good.
真香哪
Yeah. Smells so good.
好香啊
What are you cooking?
做什么好吃的哪
Wash your hands first.
洗手去啊
What's in the pot?
锅里什么呀
Turtle soup.
甲鱼汤
Gross.
算了吧
What soup?
什么汤
Lanxiang,
兰香姐
Meng'an told me about your decision.
梦安跟我说了
You can stay here and work for us,
你就踏踏实实
there's no need to worry.
在我们家做
I was going to tell you about this.
我还刚要跟你说这事呢
If you don't want to hire me,
你要是不乐意的话
feel free to tell me.
别勉强
I want to.
不勉强
I'm happy you're here.
挺好的
After all, you're my cousin.
咱们是亲戚嘛
Relax.
放心
Lin,
临临
you're still the boy I know.
这么多年你都没变
Such a nice man.
真是个好男人
So, it's turtle soup.
甲鱼汤啊
Turtle,
甲鱼
nice.
挺好
How much is it?
现在多少钱一斤啊
I didn't buy it.
不是我买的
Your in-laws came.
老丈人 丈母娘来了
They brought the turtle.
他们买的
They were here?
他们来了
They said Meng'an needs more nutrients.
说要给梦安补一补
You mean,
那 那会儿
she's home when they came?
梦安也在家
Yes.
在啊
I'll leave you alone.
你忙 你忙
Honey.
老公
[Honey,]
喂 老婆
[when will you be back?]
你什么时候回来
It may take a while.
我一时半会儿回不去了
I'm at Xin's home.
在心心家呢
I know.
我知道
But the turtle is ready.
这不甲鱼都炖上了
Should we wait for you?
我们一起等你
No. You go ahead
你们先吃吧
and eat without me.
别等我了
Bye.
挂了
Hello?
喂
You've never on my side,
一有事 你就向着外人
always supporting other people.
你 你从来都不向着我
I don't want to talk to you.
我不要你
I want mum.
我要去找妈妈
Alright. Calm down.
行了 行了
Stop crying.
别委屈了啊
Of course I'm on your side.
我能不向着你吗
I'm your sister.
我是你姐
I'm always stand by your side.
我不向着你 向着谁啊
Didn't you see the truth, today?
你今天看到了吧
Your beloved
这就是你一直
brother-in-law
护着的好妹夫
has been lying to
他一直在哄我
and hiding things from me.
骗我
He treats me like a fool.
拿我当傻子
You want to hear the truth?
想不想听两句实话
No.
不想
Well, I'll still tell you.
不想我也得说
No one
人呢
is perfect.
都会犯错
Jia Haowen's fault is
这贾浩文错在
that he contacted with his ex
说他跟前女友联系
without telling you first.
没有告诉你
He didn't do it right, yes.
确实做得不对
But,
但是
you saw it yourself,
你也看见了
he didn't betray you
他没有什么花花肠子
or do anything wrong,
也没有出轨
you have to admit it,
这你不得不承认吧
right?
是不是
But you,
那换回来说你哈
you'd never trusted him.
你不信任他
You hired someone to follow him.
找个狗仔去跟踪他
It's illegal,
你知不知道这样
you know?
是违法的
Think about it.
你想想这两件事
Between you and him,
你俩谁的性质
who's worse?
更恶劣一点呢
He is. Definitely.
当然是他了
Lying is the worst crime.
欺骗是最大的罪
Do you want to
你还想不想
enjoy your marriage or not?
好好过日子了
You are yelling at me. Again.
你看你又凶我
He lied to me and you blame me.
是他哄我骗我
Are you really my sister?
你是谁姐姐啊
I am.
我肯定是你姐呀
If I'm not,
不是你姐
I wouldn't be here with you.
我坐这儿干吗呢
What else do you want?
那你想怎么着
You followed him,
查也查了
interrupted his meeting,
见也见了
and found nothing.
屁事没有
What else can you do?
还想怎么的
Can you just cut these farces out
咱能不能不闹了
and build a life with your husband?
踏踏实实过日子
Will you,
它不好吗
Xin?
心心
He...
那他
he didn't blame me for my investigation,
他不追究我查他的事
maybe because he's guilty of something.
没准是他心里有鬼呢
Maybe,
那说不定
he's hiding a lot of things
今天只是冰山一角
from me, today's meeting
他瞒着我的事
is merely the tip of the iceberg.
指不定有多少呢
How many exes does Jia have?
老贾有几个前女友啊
He told me he has only one.
他跟我说就一个
I don't believe it.
那我还真有点不太信
See?
你看
You don't believe him, either!
你看你也这么说吧
An,
姐
is it possible
有没有这种可能啊
that
就是
Jia paid off the paparazzi I hired
老贾他也买通了狗仔
and hid
然后隐瞒了
videos with real problems.
真正有问题的视频
By giving me
只让我看到
videos I watched today,
我今天看到的
he's trying to conceal bigger problems?
是为了隐瞒更大的阴谋
Stop making up stories.
你去写小说吧
Hello.
喂 你好
[Hello.]
你好
Can you tell me the class schedule
我想问一下你们那个
of your training program for
国际注册内部审计师
CIA, SAC
证券从业资格
and Securities Sales tests?
和证券销售的培训时间
[There are classes from Monday to Friday.]
时间是周一到周五
How about Saturday?
周六没有吗
[There is no class on Saturday.]
没有
Okay, I see.
好的好的 那我知道了
I'll think about it. Thank you.
我再想想吧 谢谢啊
[OK.]
好的
Wanzhen,
婉真
Fei and Wu,
菲菲 小吴
later, our regional manager will give
地区老总晚上
some friends of him a room tour.
要带几个朋友来看房
Get prepared.
你们都准备准备
Wanzhen,
婉真
you'll responsible for entertaining
接待和统筹这块
guests and room tour planning.
就交给你了
Got it.
好 我知道了
Wanzhen,
婉真姐
I think it's time for you
你这会儿是不是
to take your kids home.
该接孩子去了
Wanzhen,
婉真
any problems?
晚上时间有困难吗
No. I got it all figured out.
没事 我已经安排好了
Good.
好
Go get ready.
那都准备吧
Dinner is served!
吃饭啦
Time to eat!
都出来吃饭啦
Lanxiang,
兰香姐
I need to pick up Meng'an.
我去接下梦安
You can eat without us.
你们先吃啊
Yunjie,
云阶啊
I made some rice cakes for you,
我给你做了米粿
do you want to have some?
你要不要先吃啊
[I'll wait for my parents to eat together.]
我等我爸妈回来一起吃
Hi, auntie.
喂 阿姨啊
Miss Chen.
喂 小陈啊
Today, I may return
我今天晚上可能要
after 9 o'clock.
九点之后才能回去
Miss Chen,
小陈啊
I have other arrangements.
我这后面还有事呢
I'll double your salary.
我给你双倍的费用
It's not about the money.
不是钱的问题
We agreed that
这我们说好了
I would work until 7 o'clock every day.
到七点钟的嘛
[In fact,]
这关键
[I need to go to another house.]
我后面还有一单
[They are waiting for me.]
人家等着我呢
Your kids
咱家两个孩子
are both cuties
都那么可爱
and always well-behaved.
又那么乖
They should be fine
在家等两个小时
to stay home alone for only 2 hours.
应该没啥事的吧
Mum,
妈妈
we got 100 in the test.
我们都考了一百分
[Mine is better.]
我的一百分比较厉害
You are amazing!
你们俩太棒了
Mum,
妈妈
when will you be home?
你什么时候下班回家呀
Wanzhen,
婉真
hurry up.
抓紧啊
Clients are on their way.
客户在路上了
Got it.
我知道了
Auntie,
阿姨
I'll get someone to take over the kids.
七点钟我找人接你的班
Great.
好嘞 好嘞
Come,
来
do your homework.
回来做作业
OK.
好
Your mother will be back soon.
妈妈晚点就回来了
We know.
知道
Alright.
好
Yunjie,
云阶啊
have the rice cakes when they're hot.
这米粿凉了就不好吃了
What are you doing?
你这忙什么呢
The school is planning
我们学校要
a donation to kids in west mountain areas.
捐给西部山区
Donation?
捐
You'll give this away?
这件也捐啊
This is beautiful.
真好看
It's barely used.
这都没怎么穿过呀
It's charity, not throwing garbage.
捐当然要捐好的啦
Chari...
这
Yunjie,
云阶
can you
表姑跟你商量个事呗
give these bright coats
你把这几件鲜亮的
to me?
给我留着呗
You'll wear them?
你要穿呀
No,
不
for your cousin Pingping.
给你萍萍姐
She's about your height.
她个头跟你差不多高
About my height?
跟我差不多高
How old is she?
她多大了
Are you kidding?
别逗了
These coats are overly childish to me,
我都嫌幼稚了
let alone her.
还给她穿
No,
不不不 不
they're not childish.
不幼稚
They are beautiful.
多好看
See, there's a cute bunny here.
你看还有个小兔子
And the colour...
你这 颜色
These would fit her well. Really.
她穿挺合适的 真的
Yunjie,
云阶啊
you know,
你看啊
my hometown is also
表姑老家那边呢
in the mountain areas.
也是贫困山区
You can
要不然
directly give these to me.
你捐给我是一样的
Right?
你说呢
Well, you can have all of them.
剩下都给你了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Thank you so much.
谢谢你 谢谢你
Look,
你看这件
this one seems fit for me, huh?
我是不就能穿
An,
姐
thank you for putting in
你为了我的事情
so much effort for me.
费心了啊
Here, have some.
来 吃点
No, thanks.
不吃
I have turtle soup at home.
我们家有甲鱼汤
This is way better than that.
这个比甲鱼汤还补呢
You are in the first trimester,
你现在孕早期
you can't be upset.
可不能生气啊
No need to get serious about me.
别跟我一般见识嘛
You are one of the people
你不惹我生气
I should get serious about.
没人敢惹我生气
I'm sorry.
我错了
I'll go to
我明天就去看
see a shrink tomorrow.
孕妇的心理门诊
My obstetrician
那我的主治医生也说了
already suggested me to do so.
他建议我去看看
But you can't blame me for my hysteria.
可是你不能怪我折腾啊
If I didn't to do so,
我要是不折腾的话
I wouldn't know
我怎么能知道
the other side of Jia.
老贾的另一面呢
What else do you want to know?
你到底想知道什么呢
To know that my dear hubby
知道我们家老贾
is not getting back together
他跟前女友
with his ex-girlfriend.
没有私情
They are just working together.
只有工作
By spoiling their cooperation?
然后把老公生意搅黄了
My hubby has other
那我们家老贾的生意
business partners.
又不差她这一单
Besides,
那再说了
I believe Jia would
我这么一折腾
see all these fusses
没准老贾还觉得
as symbols of love
我是爱他
and caring.
我心里在乎他呢
I'm telling you,
姐 你知道吗
loyalty maybe normal
婚姻里的忠诚啊
in average middle-class families,
在很多家庭是标配
but definitely a rarity in
但在我们这样的家庭
families like ours.
是顶配
It's hard.
很难的
So, you should
所以 老贾这样的老公
cherish Jia, right?
是值得珍惜的 对吧
Alright.
行
Then, drop the paparazzi
那狗仔
you're hiring. Now.
赶快给我停了
Will do.
停
You said so last time I asked.
上回你就这么说
There were balance in my account.
上回还有余额没用完呢
But they're used up.
这回真的停
Don't renew the service.
不能续费啊
Will not.
不续
Promise.
肯定不续
Nice, right?
好喝吧
Turtle soup is better.
不如我们家甲鱼汤
This way please.
来 这边请
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Please, have some tea.
两位 喝点水吧
Okay, thank you.
好 谢谢
Here you are.
喝点水
Right?
对吧
So, it's much cheaper if you pay now,
所以现在买比较划算
isn't it?
是不是
Hello? What?
喂 怎么了
[Chen Wanzhen, where are you?]
陈婉真 你在哪儿呢
Such a great mother you are!
你真行啊
If I didn't call the kids,
我要不是给孩子打视频
I wouldn't know
我都不知道你能把孩子
they are home alone.
自己扔家里边
I have work to do,
我今天要加班
will be back soon.
一会儿就回去了
The girls already had their dinner.
孩子们吃过饭了
I'm not talking about dinner!
这是吃没吃过饭的事吗
They are still children.
孩子那么小
You can not
你就把孩子自己
leave them alone at home.
扔家里边
[What if the house is on fire?]
家里着火怎么办
[Or, there is a break-in?]
家里进去人怎么办
What if a sudden power failure
停了电了
scared the kids?
把孩子吓着怎么办
I'm telling you,
我告诉你啊
whatever you're doing,
不管你现在干什么呢
drop it.
把手里事给我放下
Go back and take care of the kids.
赶紧回家给我看孩子去
I'll be back
我一会儿下班
once my job is done.
就马上回去
Career or kids,
你要忙事业
you can't have both.
那你就别耽误孩子
[Just think about it.]
你掂量掂量
[If you can't take care of them,]
自己有没有这抚养能力
I'll fly to
你别逼着我
your home
下了飞机之后
and take the custody from you.
就上你那儿接孩子去
Xin.
心心
Lin,
姐夫
come on in.
你进屋吧
You two,
你跟我姐别走了
stay and have dinner with me.
你们就在这儿吃饭
Thank you for asking.
不了
But, at home, our meal is already served.
家里饭都做好了
Yunjie is also at home
云阶这不放学
waiting for us.
在家等我们一块儿吃呢
Xiong's having classes now.
熊熊也去上课了
I don't want to eat alone.
就我自己在家吃饭
That's pathetic.
多可怜
Pathetic?
知道可怜了
You're envy us?
羡慕我跟你姐夫吗
Then, try to control your emotions,
羡慕的话就别再作了
OK?
知道吗
Later, when Jia's back,
晚上老贾回来
be nice to him
该低头低头
and ask for his forgiveness.
该认错认错
Let's go.
走吧
Good night.
走了啊
You take care.
不闹了
Drive safe.
开慢点啊
Where is Xiong?
熊熊呢
The diver is going to pick him up.
司机去接了
Where is the master?
老贾呢
He said you should eat without him.
贾总说 不用等他了
Without him.
不用等他
I want to apologize while eating...
我还想着跟他道歉呢
He'd better never come back!
不回来别回来了
I swear,
老公 我跟你说啊
I'm out of their
以后他们家的事
family drama forever.
我是不管了
They have issues!
都什么跟什么呀
A drama queen
一个喜欢作
and her knight. What a pair!
一个喜欢被作
You know,
你知道
Xin hired a paparazzi spying on Jia.
心心找人偷拍贾浩文
Do you know
然后贾浩文
what he said after finding out?
跟我说什么吗
He said, that's because Xin loves him.
他说那是心心在乎他
What can
你说你让我这个
I say?
大姨姐说什么
I'm sorry
我说对不起
or thank you for tolerating Xin?
还说谢谢你啊
She really is
看看
overly dramatic.
作得够可以吧
[In my opinion, you shouldn't]
要我说啊
[intervene in the beginning.]
也就是你 多管闲事
They are in love,
人家是两口子
right?
是不是
Means they are the same kind of people.
不是一家人不进一家门
[Fire needs air, right?]
一个巴掌拍不响
You're overreacted.
就是你瞎操心
She called
一个电话过来
and you ran to her side to avenge her.
你就过去了
Well... I'm her sister.
这 那我不是她姐吗
Still, you should
那 那你得
understand the situation first,
看清楚形势啊
right?
是不是
How
这样
about I go to talk
你要不好意思说
to Jia, if you don't want to speak out.
我跟他去说
I'll tell him,
我就告诉贾浩文
to care more about his wife.
自己老婆自己哄
It's not right to
干什么 一天天的
bother my wife with his problems,
老拽着我媳妇
right?
是吧
[You're my wife]
你是我媳妇
and I'm worried about you.
我还心疼呢
Besides, you're pregnant.
你还怀着孩子呢
[They can always call for]
家庭矛盾
family counseling
解决不了
if there is problem.
找居委会
When family counseling doesn't work,
再不行
they can call the police.
找警察
Great idea.
这招儿好
They should call the police for help.
有困难 找警察
Yes.
对
Slow down. You may choke yourself.
慢点 别噎着
There still are plenty of them.
还有呢
These are so good.
太好吃了
You like it?
喜欢吃
I'll make them for you later.
表姑经常给你做
Auntie,
表姑
why didn't you send Pingping to school?
为啥不让萍萍姐读书啊
She's a girl.
女孩子家家的
Girls need to learn nothing,
读什么书啊
but how to have a successful marriage.
将来还不是要嫁人
But, she has the right to
那也不能剥夺她
education.
读书的权利啊
Boys and girls are equal on the education.
男女是平等的
You can't force her to sacrifice for brother.
不能让萍萍姐当扶弟魔
What?
什么魔
Sacrifice.
扶弟魔
Means she gives up her future,
就是牺牲自己
to support her younger brother.
帮扶弟弟的姐姐
That's unfair.
这太不公平了
That's all older sisters' duty.
姐姐哪有不帮弟弟的
Your father's older sister
那你爸小的时候
sacrificed for him when he was young.
还不全靠你大姑啊
I remember that
我记得有一回啊
your father was bullied by other kids.
你爸被一帮小坏孩欺负
They laughed at his mother was not round.
骂他是没娘的孩子
He was furious and sad.
把你爸气得啊
His snot became a
那鼻涕
perfect bridge between his nose and mouth while crying.
那么长 哭得
When your aunt came back from work,
你大姑回来一看
she waved a huge needle
拿着这么长一个大头针
and chased down
就追着那帮坏孩子
those bad boys.
满村跑呀
One of them got so scared,
有一个小男孩
[that he peed on himself.]
都吓得尿了裤子了
Your father was so happy after that.
可给你爸解了气了
My aunt was so cool.
大姑以前这么厉害呀
Cool as hell.
那可不吗
That's what a sister would do.
所以这就是亲姐弟
[You don't understand the feeling.]
你现在还不理解
But when your mother
等你妈肚子里的
give birth to the second child,
孩子生出来
you will.
你就理解啦
They didn't tell you?
你爸妈没告诉你啊
Yunjie, where are you going?
去哪儿啊 云阶
Liars!
骗子
Where are you going?
你去哪儿啊
What happened?
怎么了 姐
An,
弟妹
I let it slip
你怀孕的事
that you're pregnant.
我给说漏嘴了
[Liars!]
骗子
They are all liars!
都是骗子
[Everybody knows,]
所有人都知道
[but me,]
就瞒着我一个人
[the hell?]
是吧
[Liars!]
骗子
They are all liars!
都是骗子
Everybody knows,
所有人都知道
but me,
就瞒着我一个人
the hell?
是吧
Always told me to be true,
不让我撒谎
yet they are full of it!
自己撒谎是吗
Can't they trust me a little?
就不能坦诚相待点吗
A pack of lying hypocrites!
谎话连篇
One wouldn't kick up a fuss,
真正的心寒
when one have truly been hurt.
不是大吵大闹
Yunjie,
云阶
chill up.
我都习惯了
I was
你们家这情况啊
in your position, too.
跟我们家当时一模一样
Actually, you are better than me.
你这还算发现得早的
My parents didn't
我当时
told me until the baby was born.
我妈都生了我才知道
They told me that
他们一直骗我说
my mother was just gaining some harmless weight.
我妈是发胖发福
Because of that,
这整的
for a long while, I thought
我还以为女人中年发福
middle-aged spread means to suddenly rise like a balloon.
都胖得跟吹气球一样
We are family.
同住一屋檐下
Why can't they
为什么就不能
tell me the truth?
坦诚相待呢
I thought there is no secret between us!
有什么不能跟我说的呀
I was told that you're sick
还说生病了
and needed more rest!
在家里养病
I believed you and was so worried!
亏了我当时那么照顾你
What? I need to be honest
不让我撒谎
while you lie all the time?!
自己谎话连篇
That's what adults do.
大人都是这样的
I thought
我以为
you're hiding it from Jing
就瞒着静姐
and An's parents.
和老丈人家呢
[I didn't know]
我没想到
[you didn't tell Yunjie.]
连云阶也不知道
I'm so sorry.
实在是对不起啊
I'll take her home.
我去接云阶吧
I called He Lu's father,
问过何璐爸爸了
Yunjie's there.
在他们家呢
Don't.
不用
She'll know it eventually.
还没做好心理建设吗
But this is all very sudden...
这也太突然了
So, you need to calm down.
所以你现在得冷静啊
For now, leave her alone.
你就让她在那儿待着吧
Give her space to let off.
跟小姐妹一块儿骂一骂
She'll feel better after.
等她出气了就好了
Later, I'll go and pick her up.
晚点我去接她
Lanxiang,
兰香姐
it's not your fault.
你也不用特别自责
We were
这事本来
planning to tell her
我们俩也商量着
in a couple of days.
这两天就告诉她了
It's alright.
没事
She just got the news earlier.
不就早了两天吗
Let's eat.
吃饭
What an amazing appetite you have!
胃口还真好
Yet, my daughter may not
也不知道我闺女
have eaten anything.
吃没吃饭
I'm sure her appetite is better than mine.
她没准吃得比我还香呢
The baby is an accident.
我妈是意外怀孕的
They said she almost lost it some days ago.
前段时间还差点保不住
I don't know why they hide it from me.
我也不知道是什么意思
Maybe,
大概
they haven't made up their mind,
就是还没有确定下来
so they didn't tell me.
所以才没跟我说的
Honey, you're so sweet.
傻白甜
Don't rationalize their lies.
你就别给他们找理由了
You really
我看呀
should change your name
你也别叫李云阶了
into Li Sweet.
改名叫李天真吧
How did you feel when you knew
你知道自己有弟弟之后
you got a baby brother?
是什么感觉啊
Like hell.
特别不好
Oh,
对了
your baby brother,
你那弟弟
it's still an embryo, isn't it?
不是还没生出来呢吗
What do you mean?
你什么意思啊
I mean, you can stop the progress!
可以不生啊
Just ask your mother
你去跟你妈说
to give up on that embryo.
让她不要这个孩子
I don't think that's a good idea.
这不太好吧
In fact,
其实
I'm angry because they lied to me.
我只是讨厌他们骗我
I don't
我对二胎
dislike the idea to have a sibling.
倒也没有那么的反感
Wait till he comes out.
等你弟弟生出来
You'll regret.
你就傻了
I want it to be a sister.
我想要个妹妹
It will be too late
总有一天
when you realize
当你发现
that your parents
你爸妈
are not care about
不再喜欢你
and loving you
不再对你好的时候
like before.
就晚了
I just called
我刚刚给你爸爸
your father
打电话了
and you both heard it.
你们也听到了
I'm really sent by your father
我真的是你爸爸
to look after you.
派来照顾你们的
Then, open up.
那给她开门吧
No.
不行
I don't know you.
我不认识你
Mum said that
妈妈说了
we shouldn't let strangers get in our home.
不能给陌生人开门的
These are my working ID and ID card.
这是我的工卡和身份证
I'm really here to look after you.
我真的是来照顾你们的
Your cards can't prove
那也不能证明
that you're not a bad person.
你不是坏人呀
Sorry.
那对不起了 姐姐
We can't let you in.
我们不能给你开门
Hello?
您好
Are you calling Chen Wanzhen's home?
您是到陈婉真家吗
Yes.
对
The kids' father is my boss.
我是她爸爸公司的员工
He sent me to babysit them.
派我过来照顾她们
But they refuse to let me in.
但是小孩一直不给开门
These are my working ID and ID card.
这是我的工牌和身份证
Can I take a better look of them?
我能确认一下吗
Excuse me.
不好意思啊
Okay, thank you.
好 谢谢啊
Just a minute, please.
您稍等一下
Wan, Zhen,
婉婉 真真
it's me,
是我呀
the doctor?
医生叔叔
So, I just confirmed that this young lady
这样的 这个姐姐呢
is truly the babysitter
确实是你爸爸公司
sent by your father.
派来照顾你们的
I checked everything already.
我已经确认过了
How about
这样
I go up
我陪着姐姐一块儿上去
with her?
好不好
I bought some fruits,
我正好买了点水果
we can share them together.
我们一块儿吃
OK.
好呀
Yes.
好
Good.
好嘞
Let's go.
走吧
Thank you.
谢谢
[The door's open.]
门锁已打开
Mum, I'm home.
妈妈 我回来了
You're back.
回来啦
Here,
来
tell me,
妈妈问你个问题啊
does any kids
你们班上
in your class, whose parents
有没有爸爸妈妈
are divorced?
离婚的小朋友啊
Yes.
有啊
Howze transferred to
浩泽就是因为
another kindergarten
爸妈离婚了
because his parents divorced.
所以转走了
He was my best friend.
他本来是我最好的朋友
Don't divorce, please.
我不要爸爸妈妈离婚
Dad, I don't want it.
爸爸不要
We'll not.
好好好
No.
不要
I don't want it, mum.
妈妈不要
Xin, why did you...
心 你跟他
It's alright.
好了 好了
Sweetheart,
宝贝
don't cry.
不哭了啊
It's okay. Honey.
行了行了行了 好儿子
My good boy.
乖乖乖
Put down your things.
把壶和书包放回去
It's okay.
不哭了
Come here,
来 宝贝
come.
来来来
I thought you're taking me home.
不是来接我回家的吗
Why we're here?
带我来这儿干吗呀
I want to make a small talk with you.
这不想跟你聊聊吗
I don't want.
我不想聊
Girl, when I propose something,
给你台阶了
you'd better accept it.
赶快给我下来啊
How can you do this to me, mother?
妈 你怎么想的呀
How can you blame me
你是怎么做到
for lying
理直气壮地指责我撒谎
and then lie to me
自己还脸不红
all the time?
心不跳的呀
Human beings are complicated.
人嘛 都是很复杂的
And the complication grows with age.
年纪越大就越复杂
I, too, hate what I am now.
我也很讨厌这样的自己
You mean I'm stupid.
就是说我傻呗
No. Of course not.
那没有啊
I just feel bad about lying to you.
妈这不是心虚吗
You still believe it's a black-and-white world.
妈还是很羡慕你
I envy you for it.
单纯可爱的样子
Mum,
妈
do you remember,
你记得吗
at this place,
就在这个地方
exact the same spot
位置都是一样的
you told me
你说过
you would only have one kid. Which is me.
只想要我一个宝宝的
I break my word, I'm sorry.
妈食言了
But I promise,
但是我跟你保证啊
I meant it
那个时候
by then.
是真的没想要的
How about now?
那现在呢
Why did you change your mind?
为什么突然又想要了呀
Just...
就是
well, it's a sudden decision.
突然间的一个决定呗
I don't want to make
也不想让你爸
your father sad anymore.
再伤心难过
What's it to do with dad?
这跟我爸有什么关系啊
I believe
现在算算
it's about 15 years ago,
应该是十五年前了吧
I was in Beijing,
那个时候我在北京漂着
in between jobs at the moment.
也没有工作
Your father
你爸呢
was about to get his master's degree.
研究生要毕业
His professor told him to apply for PhD.
导师让他考博士生
But I was pregnant.
刚好我怀孕了
You came.
有你了
I decided to go home.
我就想回老家
And, your father, gave up his academic future
结果你爸毅然决然地
and came back with me.
就跟着我回来了
He missed a great opportunity.
你爸错过了很好的机会
I don't want to
我也不想
push him to give up anything anymore.
再让他失去什么
Dad loves you so much.
看来老爸真的很爱你啊
He loves you more.
他更爱你
He wants to protect
他是不想让我们母女俩
both of us.
有任何的缺失
That's why we are a happy family.
我们才有了这个家
That's why we have
有了这么
a happy life.
幸福的生活
Honestly speaking,
其实
I don't
我对你们
dislike the idea
再要不要一个宝宝
to have a sibling.
没有那么地反感
I just hate that
我反感的是
you don't tell me anything.
你们什么都不告诉我
You told me nothing
之前
when dad lost his job
老爸失业
and you decided
还有你要卖车
to sell the car.
都瞒着我
Auntie Lanxiang is new here.
这表姑才来家里几天呀
But you told her about the baby,
你们告诉她
not me.
都不告诉我
Are all adults natural allies?
你们大人都是一伙的吗
I swear that
这个我跟你保证啊
we didn't tell Lanxiang
你兰香表姑
anything about the baby.
绝对不是我们告诉她的
She somehow figured it out herself.
那是她自己猜出来的
She's a mother, after all.
她生过孩子的呀
About the undemocratic situation
至于前段时间
within our family,
家里确实不太民主了
I apologize.
这个妈妈跟你道歉
And I hope you could
也希望你能够
forgive mum and dad.
原谅爸爸妈妈
We won't let it happen again,
我保证以后不会了
OK?
好吗
So, the illness
那你前段时间说生病了
was also a lie?
也是骗我的吗
That's not.
没有
I truly didn't feel well.
也是真的
I'm over 40,
毕竟 妈都四十多了
it's normal that I don't feel well
身体有一点
every now and then.
小毛病很正常
Besides, I'm pregnant.
现在 又怀孕
Well,
这么说吧
it's like
打个比方啊
there is a seedling
妈妈肚子里边呢
growing in my belly.
现在有一棵小苗
What kind of seedling?
什么苗啊
What do you think?
你说呢
How about a grape vine?
葡萄苗吧
I like grape.
我喜欢葡萄
Then grape vine it is.
那就葡萄苗吧